<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Yuan Gao on </title>
    <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dr. Yuan Gao on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://yuangaogao.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/backups/</guid>
      <description>Dong, H., and Y. Gao. “Existence and uniqueness of bounded stable solutions to the Peierls–Nabarro model for curved dislocations.” Calculus of Variations and Partial Differential Equations 60, no. 2 (April 1, 2021). https://doi.org/10.1007/s00526-021-01939-1. Full text here: Gao, Y., X. Y. Lu, and C. Wang. “Regularity and monotonicity for solutions to a continuum model of epitaxial growth with nonlocal elastic effects.” Advances in Calculus of Variations, January 1, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1515/acv-2020-0114. Full text here: Gao, Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activities | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/activity/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Activities We are organizing PSU-Purdue-UMD Joint Seminar on Mathematical Data Science. Time: 10:30 - 11:30 AM ET on Mondays. December 2024:
Invited speaker in Biophysical Seminars at Physics department, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, December 3, 2024. November 2024:
Invited speaker in seminar at the Center for Stability, Instability, and Turbulence, NYU Abu Dhabi, online, November 20, 2024.
Invited speaker in Numerical Analysis Seminar, University of Maryland, College Park, MD, November 5, 2024.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description> Email: foo@xyz.com Phone: +91-123123 Mailing Address 221B, Baker Street
London
United Kingdom
Social Facebook Twitter Google+ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Mailing Address 06 Physics Building, Durham, NC 27708
120 Science Drive, Durham, NC 27708
* Email: yg86@duke.edu * Phone: +91-123123 * Profile in Math Department </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Yuan Gao Assistant Professor of Mathematics
Department of Mathematics, Purdue University Email：gao662@purdue.edu Find me on Google Scholar or ResearchGate. I mainly work on analysis/computations for PDEs from materials sciences, biology, and microfluids. I recently focus on optimal control and Hamilton-Jacobi equations with applications in transition path theory, mean-field limit, large deviation principle and non-equilibrium chemical reactions.
My research is supported by NSF Award DMS-2204288. PSU-Purdue-UMD Joint Seminar on Mathematical Data Science Appointments &amp;amp; Affiliations Assistant Professor of Mathematics, Department of Mathematics, Purdue University, 2021-Now William W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Publication List 1. Preprints: [6] Gao, Y., S. Patrizi. &amp;ldquo;Slow Patterns in Multilayer Dislocation Evolution with Dynamic Boundary Conditions&amp;rdquo;, submitted. https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.05962
[5] Gao, Y., A. Stephan. &amp;ldquo;Fast-slow chemical reactions: convergence of Hamilton-Jacobi equation and variational representation&amp;rdquo;, submitted. https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.14411v1
[4] Gao, Y., Q. J. Lang, F. Lu. &amp;ldquo;Self-test loss functions for learning weak-form operators and gradient flows&amp;rdquo;, submitted. https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.03506
[3]Gao, Y., W. Li, J. -G. Liu. &amp;ldquo;Fluctuations in Wasserstein dynamics on Graphs&amp;rdquo;, submitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Recent Projects 1. Macroscopic Dynamics for Nonequilibrium Chemical Reactions Most biochemical reactions in living cells are an open system interacting with the environment through chemostats. At a mesoscopic scale, the molecular number of each species in those biochemical reactions can be modeled by the random time-changed Poisson processes.
To characterize the macroscopic behaviors in the large volume limit, the law of large numbers in path space determines a mean-field limit nonlinear ODE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/teach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/teach/</guid>
      <description>Teaching MA 266: Ordinary Differential Equations, Purdue University, Instructor, 2025 Spring. • Syllabus; • Course Contents in BrightSpace. MA/STAT 519: Introduction to Probability, Purdue University, Instructor, 2024 Fall. • Syllabus; MA 543: Ordinary Differential Equations and Dynamical Systems, Purdue University, Instructor, 2024 Spring. • Syllabus; MA 341: Foundations of Analysis, Purdue University, Instructor, 2023 Fall. • Syllabus; MA 520: Boundary Value Problems of Differential Equations, Purdue University, Instructor, 2023 Spring. • Syllabus; Math 598: Introduction to Optimal Transport, Purdue University, Instructor, 2022 Fall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
