<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Yuan Gao on </title>
    <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dr. Yuan Gao on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://yuangaogao.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/backups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/backups/</guid>
      <description>Dong, H., and Y. Gao. “Existence and uniqueness of bounded stable solutions to the Peierls–Nabarro model for curved dislocations.” Calculus of Variations and Partial Differential Equations 60, no. 2 (April 1, 2021). https://doi.org/10.1007/s00526-021-01939-1. Full text here:  Gao, Y., X. Y. Lu, and C. Wang. “Regularity and monotonicity for solutions to a continuum model of epitaxial growth with nonlocal elastic effects.” Advances in Calculus of Variations, January 1, 2021. https://doi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activities | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/activity/</guid>
      <description>In the News  The Physics of &amp;ldquo;In-Between&amp;rdquo; is Changing Our Understanding of Physical Transitions, Duke Research Blog, April 19 2021   Upcoming Activities Novermber 2021:
 Invited speaker in Special Session “Calculus of Variation, Nonlinear Waves and their Numerical Realizations”, at the AMS sectional meeting, November 20-21, 2021.  January 2022:
 Invited speaker in Special Session “Recent Developments in Nonlocal Modeling and Analysis” at the 2022 Joint Mathematics Meetings Program, Seattle, WA, January 5-8, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description> Email: foo@xyz.com Phone: +91-123123   Mailing Address  221B, Baker Street
London
United Kingdom
  Social  Facebook Twitter Google+  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Mailing Address  06 Physics Building, Durham, NC 27708
120 Science Drive, Durham, NC 27708
  * Email: yg86@duke.edu * Phone: +91-123123 * Profile in Math Department </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Yuan Gao Assistant Professor of Mathematics
 Department of Mathematics, Purdue University Email：gao662@purdue.edu Find me on Google Scholar or ResearchGate.   Appointments &amp;amp; Affiliations  Assistant Professor of Mathematics, Department of Mathematics, Purdue University, 2021-Now William W. Elliott Assistant Research Professor, Mathematics, Trinity College of Arts &amp;amp; Sciences, Duke University, 2019-2021   Research Interests  PDE analysis and multiscale modeling in materials sciences  Crystal growth: high order degenerate parabolic equations, singularity characterization, hydrodynamic limit Dislocation: vectorial nonlocal Ginzburg-Landau systems, dynamic boundary condition, rigidity, metastability and slow motion   Numerical analysis and simulations for interface dynamics  Obstacle problem: contact line dynamics, lubrication approximation, phase field model, nonlocal model, surfactant dynamics   Applied stochastic analysis and stochastic algorithm  Reversible/irreversible Langevin dynamics: random walk on point clouds, transition path theory, optimal control, coarse-graining, ergodicity, large deviation, applications in image processing and sampling     Contact Me  Email: gao662@purdue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/pubs/</guid>
      <description>Publication List  1. Preprints:  Gao, Y., and J. -G. Liu. &amp;ldquo;Revisit of macroscopic dynamics for chemical reactions from a Hamiltonian viewpoint&amp;rdquo;, submitted. https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.05396 Gao, Y., and J. -G. Liu. &amp;ldquo;Random walk approximation for irreversible drift-diffusion process on manifold: ergodicity, unconditional stability and convergence&amp;rdquo;, submitted. https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.01344 Gao, Y., A.E. Katsevich, J.-G. Liu, J. Lu, and J.L. Marzuola. &amp;ldquo;Analysis of a fourth order exponential PDE arising from a crystal surface jump process with Metropolis-type transition rates&amp;rdquo;, to appear in Pure and Applied Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Recent Projects 1. Obstacle problem: moving contact lines, lubrication The dynamics and equilibrium of a droplet on a substrate are important problems with many practical applications such as coating, painting in industries and the adhesion of vesicles in biotechnology. Particularly, the contact line dynamics of a droplet placed on an inclined rough surface are challenging fluid mechanics problems dated back to Young in 1805. The capillary effect, which contributes the leading behaviors of the geometric motion of a small droplet, is characterized by the surface tensions on interfaces separating two different physical phases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching | Dr. Yuan Gao</title>
      <link>https://yuangaogao.github.io/teach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuangaogao.github.io/teach/</guid>
      <description>Teaching  MATH 212D: Multivariable Calculus, Duke University, Instructor, 2021 MATH 712D: Multivariable Calculus, Duke University, Instructor, 2021 MATH 353: Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations, Duke University, Instructor, 2020 MATH 753: Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations, Duke University, Instructor, 2020 K_MATH 101: Calculus, Duke University, Instructor, 2019 K_MATH 201: Multivariable Calculus, Duke University, Instructor, 2019 MATH 353: Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations, Duke University, Instructor, 2019 MATH 557: Introduction to Partial Differential Equations, Duke University, Instructor, 2019 MATH 753: Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations, Duke University, Instructor, 2019 Math 5351: Mathematical Methods in Science and Engineering, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Instructor, 2018 Calculus 1B, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Instructor, 2017 Operations Research, Fudan University, Instructor, 2013&amp;amp;2014 Mathematical Analysis/Functional analysis, Fudan University, TA, 2012&amp;amp;2013  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
